<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visualization on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</title>
    <link>/tags/visualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visualization on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment</title>
      <link>/findings/employment_page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/employment_page/</guid>
      <description>Background A discussion of factors related to incarceration would be remiss without discussing unemployment. Empirical analyses have consistently found unemployment to be one of the factors most strongly correlated with crime. A 2005 meta-analysis of over 200 studies quantifying predictors of crime found that local unemployment rates had the second-largest effect size out of 31 predictors.1 There are several reasonable theories as to why this is true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arrests</title>
      <link>/findings/arrests_page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/arrests_page/</guid>
      <description> Total arrests  Drug arrests  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Structure</title>
      <link>/findings/family_structure_page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/family_structure_page/</guid>
      <description>There were many government data sources used for this research, most prominent of which were the Center for Disease and Prevention’s (CDC) and Department of Health and Human Services (HHS)’ many articles regarding teen births. Other sources include the County Health Rankings website, Youth.gov website, Guttmacher Institute, Child Trends website, and the National Center for Biotechnology Information (NCBI). Many of these sources had information up to 2018, which is still relevant for statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>/findings/housing_page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/housing_page/</guid>
      <description>Background Despite being previously overshadowed in the literature, housing affordability has recently begun to situate itself at the center of efforts to transition incarcerated people back into the community after release. Many now see access to affordable housing as one of the primary limiting factors for reentering individuals; an unstable living situation can severely impact employment opportunities, predispose individuals to returning to criminal activity, and hinder efforts to reestablish family relationships and friendships1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>